Do good and the end will be bad, the end of the good will be bad because the end is that the
good will be bad.  You will say, Sir,
what are you talking about today?  Hey brother,
I want to share some great news with you today.
Who is from the insurance world.   Any of
you please type in the comment box
or press the like button if you
want GST to be removed from insurance.   May
my client benefit.  All of you who
wanted that
GST should be removed so that my client would benefit, either
write yes in the comment box or press the like button.
Now first of all do this work, press
friends and your
wish will be fulfilled on 22 September 2025.
Many of our seniors met us and
went to the government.  We sent mails, messages
, letters and the government said that
GST on insurance premium has been abolished from September 22, 2025.  As soon as this
news came, most of us
agents
informed our clients that Sir, now your
GST is over.  In products like term,
18% was charged on mediclaim and you all
happily conveyed this message to your clients.
Sir, your premium is now reducing by 18%.
How many people did it, sir?  Say yes once
in the comment box because
today's session of this news is about that.  You all
did all this and the premium became cheaper but
friends, for us, the
story became completely different for the LIC advisor and the Mediclaim advisor.
Because when the company used to
give us commission, that was inclusive, what is happening now
?
Prepare to be inclusive.  Meaning earlier we used to get
exclusive.  Now I will
explain it with calculations and examples.  The exclusive
word was exclusive GST.  Now
inclusion of GST is happening.  And the result of this will be that
your commission income with which you are
running your family will be reduced by 18%.  The
blame for the removal of GST is being put on you.
I don't think you've probably been told that much yet.
Some companies started issuing letters.
First let me tell you with simple legumes.  I am
not taking actual commission as per very simple calculation.
For simple calculation, suppose you
deposited a premium of Rs 10,000 and you get only 10%
income on it.  The income you have with which you are
running your family.  Remember this world,
you were running your family with the same commission.
Now, on the premium of Rs 10,000, you used to get 10%
commission i.e. Rs 1000 and exclusive
means GST was given separately on top of that, Rs 180,
so your total income was Rs 180.
Now those people who got GST advisor and felt that
GST was beneficial, they used to give Rs
1000, still there was a net amount left in their pocket,
but now see what happened, the earlier one was Rs
1180, but now it has become inclusive,
now a new thing is coming, inclusive of GST means
which is 10%, it is with GST.  So now
18% GST will be deducted from the commission of Rs. 1000 that you received.  This
means approximately ₹153
GST will be deducted.  Earlier you used to get
₹180, now ₹153 has been deducted from it.  So 110 which
we were getting extra.  Instead of 1180,
now we have ₹1000 left in our pocket
and for those who do not have GST, we would have got 1180 but the
main thing is that now we will have approximately ₹847 left
in our pocket and if I see,
this 800 847 means roughly, I am talking about a round
figure.  You are prepared to lose 15% commission.
Open your eyes.
Open your ears.  You gave ₹100.  Reduced by ₹150.
152 So I'm talking in rounds.
Reduced by ₹150.  If you paid a premium of Rs 10,000,
your commission would have
reduced by Rs 150.  If you pay a monthly premium of Rs 5 lakh
in mediclaim or
insurance, then how much loss did you incur
?   If you
give 10 lakhs for 1500 rupees on one lakh, then the
income of up to 75000 rupees means that people who are doing decent work in a year are
ready to be cheated of five to seven lakhs to 10 lakhs.
I am asking you, is this why you used to
say that GST should be removed so that your
income also reduces.  That's why I said in the beginning that if you do
good, the end will be bad.  Friends,
but the government is making this change so that
our insurance
company will not get input tax.  This
means the company did not suffer any loss.  So is there
an advisory left to bear the losses
?  I am asking this question to all of you
only with the intention that the company should not suffer any loss, the
government should not suffer any loss, the client should not suffer any loss.  If there is any
loss, it should be of the LIC agent.  Are you sleeping
?  You guys have to get up.   You have to
wake up and I
want to wake you up through this video.  Otherwise, you have become a
victim of a huge conspiracy.
Our commissions are already being reduced.
You see, commissions have reduced in life insurance.
If your
claim ratio in Mediclaim is low or has reduced due to many things, then on
top of that this blow
is ready to be felt.  So friends, this is just the beginning.
I want to tell you something.  First
thing, check your commission seal.  What is written on it
?  Exclusive GST or
Inclusive GST?  Note this down.  Check the contact
wording that is with your insurance company.
What is written in it?  Exclusive or
inclusive?
Because when we do it, then we will have to gather.
You take it quietly.  He
is ready to give 15% commission happily.  You have to get ready.  I will have to get up.  Take
care of all your bills and the commission bills that you get, and I want to say this
brothers, in the end, on one hand we are happy
that the client benefited, on the
other hand we are happy that the
government accepted our point, but we are sad that the
money with which we were earning our livelihood,
running our family, our income is being hit, the
government is not making any difference
because it has stopped the input credit.
He is getting it in full.  The company
put the losses it was incurring on us.
Whom should we tell friends, are you ready to check
?  I have a request from you.
Just check your commission.  Keep it safe
and tell me in the comment section
which company you are from and
give the name of the exclusive or company in it.  Exclusive or
inclusive
and I want to create another session after this.
If you want me to tell you
how to negotiate with the company?  If you want
everything about how to file a complaint in IDM and what is written,
I will give it to you.  You
write in the comment box, Yes Sharma Sir, write this.
I understand that you are looking for a ready-made negotiation
script.  You want to know
what to send as complaint but I will
give it to you soon.  Friends, wake up, unite
and
save your commission.  This may
not be the last fight.  Next time the government is
cutting 15% today from some flows again.  Then she will cut you off on some pretext
and you will just keep watching.  Jai
Hind Jai Bharat Jai Insurance Advisor.  I,
Sharma Sir, am a friend and a partner in your insurance growth.